<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Alex Roos</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Alex Roos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Portfolio Website</title>
      <link>/projects/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>Check this website out on GitHub!
 Working with Hugo through Doom Emacs and org-mode A big fascination of mine has always been hosting websites. Being in full control over a site on the internet allows communication with the entire globe. Therefore, I began learning about webhosting.
Along my journey I discovered Hugo - a static site generator. Hugo uses markdown files to generate beautiful, lean webpages, which makes it ideal for blogs or a website like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BeInCrypto Educational Telegram Bot</title>
      <link>/projects/beincrypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/beincrypto/</guid>
      <description>Check the code out on GitHub!
 Using programming skills for real world value In the summer of 2020 I was working as an editor in chief for the German section of BeInCrypto. While the work as a journalist and editor was certainly interesting and rewarding, by that time the passion to code had me already. So I wanted to program something that would be useful to the business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LevelUp - Tracking progress</title>
      <link>/projects/levelup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/levelup/</guid>
      <description>Check the code out on GitHub!
 My first real programm When I worked through &amp;ldquo;Automate the Boring Stuff&amp;rdquo;, I wanted to keep track of my time invested in learning Python. So the idea for a timetracker with a command line interface was born.
It was a great exercise, because my knowledge on the first version was very limited. I did not use a database, but instead an Excel-Sheet, where I would automate the input into the cells, and read the cells to calculate my total time invested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MoneroBlocksBot</title>
      <link>/projects/moneroblocksbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/moneroblocksbot/</guid>
      <description>Check the code out on GitHub!
 Playing with APIs The purpose of this bot was for me to practice using public APIs. Allthewhile I also wanted to provide some value to Monero ethusiasts on Telegram.
For this I used API provided by MoneroBlocks.info (nowadays LocalMonero.co). With the right parameters in the URL you get a json object with the appropriate information (i.e. Block Height, TXs in the last Block etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PythonScripts - Automate the boring stuff</title>
      <link>/projects/pythonscripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/pythonscripts/</guid>
      <description>Check the code out on GitHub!
 Here I have 3 different Python scripts that automate certain aspects of my workflows.
delete_txts.py When I coded my first lyrics grabber for iTunes, I had saved the lyrics for all songs in the album direcotry as a .txt.
This was not necessary, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t bother me much at first. However, since my library contains around 7.000 songs, I also had 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReputationBot</title>
      <link>/projects/reputationbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/reputationbot/</guid>
      <description>Check the code out on GitHub!
 My first real telegram bot Since I was an admin in a particular Telegram group, I wanted to use my programming knowledge to expand the utility of my group. Soon after, the idea for a Reddit-style voting bot for messages was born.
Basically, users have voting power that gets reset every 24 hours. Up- or downvoting consumes voting power. Users collect repuation over time and can &amp;ldquo;win the week&amp;rdquo;, meaning that they are the user with the most upvotes in a given week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TipXMR</title>
      <link>/projects/tipxmr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/tipxmr/</guid>
      <description>Check the project out on GitHub!
 TipXMR is by far the biggest and most complex project I have worked on so far. It all started small, in September of 2020 with the idea to support Monero donations in livestreams.
  Monero is the biggest privacy focused cryptocurrency in the world and a favorite of mine. The goal was to empower streamers to be less dependant on centralized services like YouTube or Twitch and to expand the use-case for Monero.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
